Lucas Cavalcanti Rodrigues

Links

Github Linkedin Stackoverflow

Technical Skills

OS

GNU/Linux, Windows

LANGUAGES

Python, Javascript, Rust, R

FRAMEWORK

flask, node.js, pandas, matplotlib, statsmodel, scikitlearn, sympy

DATABASES MySQL

CLOUD GCP

OTHERS Markdown, Git, Vim,

VS Code, Jira

Analytical Skills

Data Structures Algorithm Probability **Data Analysis Econometrics** Machine Learning Agile methodologies

Education

2017-2021 PHD ECONOMICS Universidade de São Paulo

2013-2014 MR. SC. IN ECONOMICS Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora

2009-2012 **B.A. IN ECONOMICS** Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora

Summary

I'm a professional with over 7 years of experience working in different areas of the data lifecycle, such as analytics and infrastructure. A significant part of this experience is due to my work as an economist, both in academia and the private sector. Since 2021, though, I have focused on data engineering and infrastructure. I have over 4 years of experience using Python, in addition to having working knowledge of a number of technologies, such as Javascript, SQL, Google Cloud, among others. I'm also a highly motivated professional, with strong organizational and multi-tasking skills, who always aim to add value to the business and the teams I work with.

Experience

CURRENT

Data Engineer

DP₆

I work on collecting and structuring data obtained from customer interaction channels such as mobile apps and websites

Python, Javascript, Google Analytics, Firebase, GTM, Data Studio

2020-2021 Economist

Parceiros da Educação

Bom Retiro · São Paulo - SP

lucas.ecomg@gmail.com

+55(11) 95600-2307

30 years

I was responsible for creating the ESG Racial Equity Index (IEER), a metric used by several companies in the Brazilian private sector to assess and monitor the status of racial inequality among their employees. In addition to develop the index, a by-product of my doctoral thesis, I was also responsible for the data infrastructure used to compute the index. The infrastructure was built using resources from the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).

Python, Pandas, GCP, Cloud Storage, Big Query, Flask

2016-2017 Data Analyst

The Center for Public Policy and Education Assessment is an institution responsible for the external assessment of the educational systems of Brazilian states and municipalities. I contributed to public policy reports directed to the subnationals Departments of Education by carrying out the statistical analysis of microdata. In these analyses, among other techniques, I used statistical methods such as Factor Analysis, Index Construction and Linear Hierarchical Models.

SPSS, Microsoft Office

Other Employment

2021-2021 Data Consultant

2016-2017 Professor of Economics

UFJF MPT

Certifications

Google Analytics Individual Qualification TOEFL ITP

Issued Aug. 2021

Issued Feb. 2019